なんば
むった
(南波 六太)
こうほせい
＜私達 宇宙飛行士候補生➡
We astronaut candidates, or ASCANs,
アスキャンが ６日間 ７０キロを
とうは
踏破する サバイバル訓練＞
are undergoing survival training in which we go seventy kilometers in six days.
＜どこまで行っても変わらない
景色の中を ただひたすら➡
Training that's extremely boring when the scenery never changes...
歩くという ジミーに
大変な訓練である＞
As part of our training, we're supposed to choose a new leader each day.
＜その道中 毎日１人ずつ交代で
チームのリーダーを決める｡➡
まぁ 学校の日直みたいなもんだ＞
Like being class monitor at school.
＜メンバーは その日のリーダーの
指示によって行動し➡
Group members must follow the orders of the day's leader,
and every action is filmed, so our performances can be judged.
それらは全て カメラによって
記録され 評価の対象となる＞
And on the day that I,
＜そして めぐりめぐって
つと
俺･南波六太がﾘｰﾀﾞｰを務める➡
Nanba Mutta, was chosen as leader,
この日に よりによって
大問題が発生したのだ！＞
we've run into some serious trouble.
＜あ～ぁ 何てこったい！＞
Man...
Are you serious?
にった
⦅新田ぁ～‼⦆
(新田)⦅は？⦆
Nitta!
⦅いてえな！何すんだ てめえ！⦆
That hurt!
What are you doing?!
⦅違うって！あれ見ろ！⦆
No! Look over there!
Thanks to Nitta's plan to press on yesterday, we've made it up to fourth.
＜昨日のリーダー･新田の
ふんばり作戦で 私達は➡
５チーム中 ４位に
ふじょう
なんとか浮上した＞
But damn that Nitta...
＜しかし新田のヤロウ
訓練中 個人的な連絡は➡
You aren't supposed to make private calls during training.
取れないはずなのに…｡あの猫の
待ち受けの携帯で 女の子と➡
But he keeps talking to some woman on that phone of his with cat wallpaper.
ちょこちょこ電話してやがる｡
サバイバル中に何て うらやま…➡
Lucky bastard...
いや けしからん！と
思っていたのだが…＞
That's outrageous!
Or so I thought...
悪い…｡
Sorry...
Huh?
(新田)ごめん…みんな｡
I'm sorry,
everyone.
I have to go back...
俺 戻るわ｡
Space Brothers
I can no longer remember
what I tried to forget
When I peeked through the telescope
I realized that our world is tiny
It was a picture of infinity
It's not a one-time thing
We'll walk together
Once we've passed the clouds,
we will hold the world between our fingers
and keep what we lost in mind
#50 Nitta and Mutta
も…戻るって｡
G-Go back?
なに言ってんだよ！新田！
What are you talking about, Nitta?
なんだ？トラブルか？ローリー！
様子を見てきてくれや！
What's going on?
Is there a problem?
Lowry, go find out what's happening.
事によっちゃ 本部に報告だ｡
(ローリー)ＯＫ！
If it's serious, we'll report to HQ.
Okay.
(ケンジ)携帯？
Your phone?
Yeah...
I still had it during yesterday's second break.
きゅうけい
昨日の二度目の休憩地点までは
確実に持ってたんだが➡
ここに来るまでの どっかで
落としちまったらしい｡
But I must have
dropped it afterward.
その前に ちょっと気になって
たんだけど なんで➡
But first, I've been wondering about something.
Why are you allowed a phone?
新田君だけ 携帯を？
きょか
許可は取ってある｡
教官に頼み込んだんだ｡➡
I received permission.
I asked the instructor for an exception.
この訓練の期間中に
大事な電話があるから➡
I'm expecting an important call during this training,
常に携帯を持たせてくれって｡
so I have to carry my phone.
大事な電話？
An important call?
こんな個人的な話で悪いんだが
今晩あたり➡
I know I'm being selfish,
but the call will probably come tonight.
かかってくるはずなんだ｡きっと｡
Anyway, you guys go ahead without me.
(新田)とにかく みんなは先へ
進んでくれ｡日が沈む前に➡
I'll find it and catch up before sunset.
俺は 携帯を探し出して
すぐ 後を追うから｡
きゃっか
その案は 却下だ！今日の
リーダーは お前じゃねえ｡
I can't let you do that.
You aren't the leader today.
いつもの 冷静｢風｣な新田は
どこ行ったんだよ｡
What's happened to the level-headed Nitta we all know and love?
単独行動なんて 宇宙飛行士が
くち
最初に口にする案じゃねえぞ｡
Astronauts aren't supposed to move on their own.
くっ…チッ！じゃあ どうすりゃ
いいんだよ リーダー！
Do you have a better idea, leader?
全員で先へ進もう！
We move together.
さあ 行くぞ新田！
Come on... Let's go, Nitta!
H-Hold on, Nanba!
ちょっ…ちょっと待ってくれ
南波！そりゃ ねえだろ！
You can't do that...
俺は１人でも大丈夫だ｡必ず
明日中に みんなと合流できる｡
I'll be fine by myself.
I promise to catch up by tomorrow morning.
だから 暗くなる前に…｡
うっせ～｡
So before it gets dark...
Shut up.
リーダーは俺だぞ 新田｡
言うこと聞けっ｡
I'm the leader, Nitta.
Do as I say.
(新田母)うん おいしい｡
Tastes delicious.
戻らせないっていう ムッ君の
考えは 正しいと思うけど…｡
I know that Mu's decision to force him into staying was correct...
ハァ ハァ…｡
(ｱﾏﾝﾃｨ)心配ありません｡
ムｯタには考えがあります｡
Don't worry.
Mutta knows what he's doing.
Huh?
(新田)ちくしょう なんで
よりによって➡
Damn...
Why did Nanba have to be the leader today?
こんな日に 南波が
リーダーなんだよ｡
それで 今晩その電話が
かかってくんだよな？
So you're expecting a call tonight, right?
新田の携帯に｡
(新田)ああ！だから
そう言ってんだろ｡
On your cell phone?
Yeah, that's what I've been saying!
だったら 着信で
てんめつ
チカチカ点滅するはずだろ｡
Then your phone should start flashing when it rings.
夜になってからの方が
見つけやすい｡
It'll be easier to spot at night.
荷物だって ジャマだろ？
キャンプ地に荷物を置いて➡
And you probably shouldn't carry all this around.
After making camp, we can leave our stuff and search once it's dark.
夜に ２人で行く｡ハァ…｡
まずは ２キロ先で
今晩の食料を見つけ出す｡
Finding the food two kilometers ahead is our first priority.
今日は それ以上先へは進まず
その場で テントを張るんだ｡
We'll set up our tents there, and stop for the night.
ウッ！ハァ…｡
匂う…｡
I can smell it...
There it is!
Once everything is ready,
準備ができたら
俺と新田の２人で…｡
Nitta and I
出発だ！
will set out.
ケンジ みんなを頼んだぞ｡
ああ｡任せてくれ｡
Kenji,
I'm trusting you to look after things here.
Sure, you can count on me.
２人とも 気をつけて！
行ってきます！
Be careful, guys.
And we're off!
《あぁっ！しまった！俺とした
ことが なんて判断ミスを…》
C-Crap!
I made a terrible mistake...
《こっちは ケンジに
頼んでも よかったんだ》
I should have asked Kenji to go with Nitta!
《ハーレムじゃん あっち！
あ～ いいな ケンジ…｡➡
Now he has his own harem!
Lucky you, Kenji...
こんな星空のもと 美人３人と
テントで わいわい…》
You get to sit in a tent under the stars, with three beautiful women...
《あ～ 時間戻してぇ！》
I wish I could turn back time!
なんで 俺と
戻る気になったんだ？
Why
did you volunteer to come with me?
ハァ ハァ…｡そりゃ まあ
お前が マジっぽかったからだ｡
Well, I guess...
Because you looked so serious.
この訓練で 誰より１位を
目指してたのは 新田だろう｡
You always cared most about finishing first.
その新田が 順位よりも 今大事な
もんがあるって言うんなら…｡
But if there's
something that's more important to you now,
we should probably make it a priority.
そっちを優先すべきなんだろうな
って 思っただけだ｡
ハァ ハァ…｡事情はまったく
分かんねえままだけどな｡
I still have no idea what it's all about though.
(新田)別に…隠すつもりは
なかったんだが➡
It wasn't that
I deliberately wanted to keep it a secret.
南波日々人と比べられるのが嫌で
言い出せなかった…｡
But I didn't him compared to Nanba Hibito, so I didn't say anything.
Huh?
俺にも１人 弟がいる｡
I also have a little brother.
(新田)今日 電話をかけてくるのが
その弟だ｡➡
He's supposed to call me today.
話すのは２年ぶりになる｡
We haven't spoken in two years.
(新田)俺は 早く弟に…｡
I just
want for my brother
部屋の外に出てもらいたいんだ｡
to decide
to leave his room.
My brother
弟は全く人と
顔を合わせようとしねえんだ｡
refuses to see anyone.
普段はおとなしいが
シャクにさわることがあると➡
He's quiet most of the time.
But if you upset him, he'll start throwing things and punching the wall.
モノを投げたり壁を殴ったり
ひでえもんだ｡➡
It's bad.
部屋から出ない理由を
聞いたって➡
If anyone asks why he won't leave his room,
｢僕にもわからない｣としか
答えない｡
he says he doesn't know.
I want
俺は…何とかしたいんだ｡➡
to do something to help.
今まで何度も そのチャンスを
逃してしまった｡
I've missed so many chances already...
たった１本の電話で どうにか
なるとも思えねえけどな…｡
I doubt one phone call will make such a difference.
(新田)何とかしたいんだ｡
But I need to do something.
《はあ くそっ！➡
Damn...
ねえな 携帯…》
I don't see it anywhere...
新田の弟 名前は？
Nitta,
what's your brother's name?
ハァ…ハァ…｡
ハァ…カズヤ｡
Kazuya.
カズヤね…｡
どんな奴？カズヤって｡
Kazuya, huh?
What's Kazuya like?
ハァ…ハァ…｡
(新田)あいつは…優しい奴だ｡
He's a gentle person.
ハァ…ハァ…｡
宇宙に関しても 子供の頃から
俺より詳しかった｡
When we were kids,
he knew much more about space than I did.
俺は後から
弟の影響を受けただけだ｡➡
I was inspired by him.
弟は中２の時 一度
不登校になったけど➡
When he was a middle school second-year,
he stopped attending school for a while.
その時は半年ほどで済んだんだ｡
But it only lasted six months.
(新田)だけど大学を中退して
バイトすら辞めて➡
But then he dropped out of college...
He even quit his part-time job...
今は何もしていない｡
２年間ずっと…｡
He doesn't do anything now.
Not for the past two years.
どうしようもねえ奴だ！
２５にもなって｡
He's completely hopeless!
I mean, he's twenty-five!
どうしようもねえ…｡
Just hopeless...
I envy you
俺は…若くして月面を踏んだ➡
for having a brother like Nanba Hibito,
南波日々人も
そんな弟を持つ南波も➡
who landed on the moon
うらやましく思うぜ…｡
at such a young age.
《こいつ…ずっと そんな風に
思ってたのか》
Is this how he's felt about me the whole time?
⦅うらやましいぜ
あんな弟がいて➡
You're lucky to have a little brother like that.
たいしたもんだよ 弟⦆
Your little brother's special.
⦅ど～ぞ お兄さん⦆
You first,
big brother.
《出会った時から ずっと…》
Ever since we first met...
Try giving Rei a call today.
れい
今日 零ちゃんに電話してみてね｡
必ず出るって言ってたから｡➡
He says he'll definitely answer.
できれば １５時過ぎる前に
かけてあげて｡➡
Try to call before 3 PM...
でないと向こうは
深夜になっちゃうから…｡
Or it'll be too late over there.
《わかってるよ｡それぐらい！》
I already know all that!
《電話して
何を話せっていうんだよ…》
What am I supposed to talk to him about?
[TV](ｷｬｽﾀｰ)お昼のニュースです｡➡
This is your news at noon.
来月の打ち上げに備え
ロシアに滞在中の➡
Azuma Takio, currently in Russia to prepare for next month's launch,
Azuma Takio to Become Second Japanese Person on the Moon!
日本人宇宙飛行士
あずま　たきお
吾妻滝夫さんが➡
Azuma Takio to Become Second Japanese Person on the Moon!
出発前の記者会見に出席しました｡
吾妻さんは➡
participated in a press conference.
Azuma will be taking the place of Nanba Hibito,
日本人１人目の月面到達者として
現在 月面に滞在中の➡
南波日々人さんと交代で
たずさ
基地の建設に携わる予定です｡➡
the first Japanese person on the moon.
南波日々人さんは現在…｡
Nanba Hibito is currently...
(新田)悪いな 南波｡
Sorry, Nanba.
こんな個人的な用事に
付き合わせちまって｡
I didn't mean to involve you in my personal problems.
気にすんな｡
Don't worry about it.
ここまで来て今さらなんだが…➡
And I hate to say it after all our backtracking,
ムダ足になるかもしれないんだ…
本当にすまない｡
but we may be wasting our time.
I really am sorry.
多分 弟は
電話をかけてこねえと思う｡
My brother probably
won't even call me.
そういう奴なんだ｡
携帯は光ってなくて➡
That's how he is.
And if my phone isn't lighting up,
すでに通り過ぎてるかもしれない｡
we may have already passed it.
もし 着信があって
見つけられたとしても➡
Even if he does call and we can spot the phone,
その１回で俺が出なけりゃ
あいつは それを➡
I still have to answer.
Or he'll think I've given up on him,
｢裏切り｣と感じて
もう二度と かけてこない｡
and he'll never call again.
《結局 俺は…
なんの役にも立たねえ兄貴か》
So in the end...
As his brother, is there no way I can help him?
大丈夫だよ 新田｡
携帯は あと４キロほど先だ｡
It'll be fine, Nitta.
We probably won't reach it for another four kilometers.
昨日の食料のあった所…
多分 あそこだ｡
It's probably near the place where yesterday's food was.
ちょっと待て…
なんで そう思うんだよ｡
Hold on...
What makes you think that?
Did you forget? About the snake?
忘れたのか？ヘビの時だ｡
Nitta!
⦅新田～っ‼⦆
そうだ！あん時だ｡
Oh! That was probably it!
走ろう 南波！
４キロなら すぐだ！
Run, Nanba!
We'll make four kilometers in no time.
えっ!?走んの？
ちょっと待て 新田！
Wait, we're running?
Hold on, Nitta...
どんだけ体力あんだ お前｡
How much energy can you have?
(新田)ハァ…ハァ…ハァ…｡
ハァ…ハァ…ハァ…ハァ…｡
⦅出て来い カズヤ！コラァ～‼⦆
Just come out, Kazuya! Seriously!
⦅いつまで そうしてる気だ！
バカ！⦆
How long are you staying in there, idiot?
⦅落ち着いて 零ちゃん！⦆
Calm down, Rei!
ハァ…ハァ…ハァ…｡
⦅ねえ お兄ちゃん｡
また山に星 見に行こうよ⦆
Hey, Bro...
Let's go stargazing on the mountain again.
⦅オリオン座流星群だって｡➡
It's the Orionid meteor shower.
ほら！すごいよ！
願いかけ放題だよ！⦆
Look, it's amazing! You can wish as much as you want!
⦅そんなに流れ星に
願いかけたいのか？➡
You have that many wishes to make on shooting stars?
流れ星の正体は
いんせき
ちっちゃい隕石だとか➡
Weren't you the one who said
that those shooting stars
are actually tiny meteorites
宇宙飛行士が捨てたゴミの
詰まった補給船だとか…｡➡
熱弁してたのはカズヤだろ⦆
or resupply vehicles carrying space junk.
(カズヤ)⦅正体は何でもいいの｡➡
That isn't important!
流れ星は一瞬で流れちゃうから
願うもんなの⦆
You wish on a shooting star because it instantly disappears.
⦅だけど こっちは…
願いかけ放題だよ！⦆
But if we go and see this, we can wish all we want.
ハァ…ハァ…｡
What was it that you wished for?
《お前の願いって…
なんだったんだ!?》
ハァ…ハァ…この辺だ｡
It was around here.
う～ ハヒィ…
あ～っ！はっ…｡
もう…ダメッ！う～っ！
No more...
ハァ…ハァ…ハァ…｡
昨日の食料箱だ！
We found the food here yesterday.
When Nanba rushed me, I was standing here.
確か この辺に立ってる時に
南波が突っ込んできて…｡
ハァ…ハァ…｡
ふ～っ｡あったか？
Did you find it?
ああ…光ってた｡
間違いなく弟だ…｡
Yeah,
it was flashing...
My brother called.
よかったじゃねえか｡
That's great news.
《俺はまた…
チャンスを逃したんだな…》
I
missed another chance.
The stones out in the fields
are worn down by their daily existence and disappear
That's their trial
When will we be able to resist fate?
Before you lose all hope
and say that we can't win against gravity
go without stopping
past the goal line
You have such strong convictions
Leave your footprints on this Earth
Maybe their tiny length will cause a miracle in the end
Give us a magnificent jump
Run now and do it
Jump past all you see overhead
This is your stride
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#51 Living Stone
＜なあ 新田｡もし カズヤと
電話で話せてたら➡
Hey, Nitta...
What were you going to tell Kazuya on the phone?
何て言うつもりだったんだ？＞
No idea.
(新田)＜分かんねえ｡
分かんねえけど…そうだな｡➡
No idea, but...
I was going to invite him to visit.
｢気が向いたら遊びに来い｣
くらいは言うつもりだった＞
Damn, man!
＜この野郎！最初は
嫌な奴だと思っていたが➡
I thought you were a jerk, but you really care about your little brother.
なんて弟思いなんだ！＞
Am I about to lose my title of ideal big brother?
＜何か ちょっと
理想の兄像として 負けてる＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Living Stone"
Will Nitta get through to his brother?
＜新田の思いは
伝わんねえのか？＞
(南波日々人)パンパカパーン！
This Week's Space Photo
Let's all support astronaut Wakata!
This week's space photo!
今週の宇宙写真です！
カッコイイ！
Cool stuff!